ZIAD HOSNY

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

ziadhosny007@gmail.com

(+2) 01110146112



in www.linkedin.com/in/ziadhosny/_

https://github.com/ZiadHosny/



PROFILE

I have 3+ years of Experience in Analyzing, Designing, Developing, and Integrating Front-End & Back-End based applications. Experience in developing applications using Typescript, React, React Native, Node js, and Express. Seeking a role as Front-end and Node js Developer.

EXPERIENCE

Apr 2024 - Now Logex Tech Company - Full stack Developer (Part Time).

I specialize in React and Node.js. I am responsible for fixing bugs and improving websites, ensuring they run smoothly and efficiently. My work includes developing and maintaining features for various projects, including the website https://life-ward.com/, where I contributed to enhancing user experience and functionality.

Jun 2023 - Now Shoaa Company - Full stack Developer (Full Time).

Developed and managed comprehensive full-stack service projects across various Egyptian government sectors, focusing on electricity consumption analysis, meter installation, reading, maintenance, and customer support. Collaborated effectively with a dedicated team to strategize, execute, and deliver high-quality solutions.

Jul 2022 - Jun 2023 Bitspire Company - Full stack Developer (Full Time).

Develop frontend and backend websites using React and Node.js. Responsibilities include creating features and interfaces from wireframes, ensuring performance and user experience, and writing clean, testable code. Implement CI/CD pipelines for efficient development and deployment, and collaborate with backend developers and designers.

Mar 2022 - Jul 2022 eSmart Company - Front-end Developer (Part Time).

Developed and managed a comprehensive scheduling system for a clinic in Saudi Arabia, optimizing appointment allocation, patient booking, and rescheduling to enhance operational efficiency for doctors

EDUCATION

Apr 2022 - Sep 2022 Information Technology Institute

Front-End & Cross-Platform Intensive Code Camp

2016 - 2020 Mansoura University

BSc in Computers and Information. (Grade: Very Good).

Graduation Project: Building a mobile learning app with a chatbot by Android, Java, Python, and NLP.

SKILLS

- React

- NodeJs

- JavaScript

- TypeScript

- Docker

- React Native

- Tailwind CSS

- Express

- Nestis

- Bootstrap

- Angular

- Postgres

- MySql

- Git

- CI CD

- Python

- Nextis

- MonogoDB

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Continuous improvement

- Good communication

- Team Work

- Problem solving

- Self Learning

LANGUAGES

- English: Professional

- Arabic: Native

Portfolio 🔗





My portfolio shows my progress, skills, and latest projects, You can contact me through it. Build Using NextJs, TypeScript, React, MUI, CSS

Quran Kareem



The Quran, also romanized Qur'an or Koran, is the central religious text of Islam, believed by Muslims to be a revelation from God. It is organized in 114 chapters which consist of individual verses. Quran Kareem App aims to provide Quran recitations by famous reciters in different narrations on the web, mobile, watch, and TV devices. The app is available on mobile, tablet, and Android TV.

Scheduler 🔗



React And JS Library Calender for clinic System by picking and rescheduling dates for doctors' appointments by Inserting or dragging dates, Adding more information about the date, and disabling holidays, which is suitable for any booking system with high performance and easy-to-use features.

Build using React, Typescript, Javascript, date-fns, MUI

Task Manager



Full Task Manager with a Nice user interface in which you can add, check tasks, and pick due dates for accomplishing tasks with filter, Edit, and delete features.

Build using React, Redux, Node, MongoDB, Express, MUI, CSS

Freshio





ITI Graduation project E-commerce for buying healthy products and protein supplies, With Categories and filters to pick products according to price and Calories per product, I was the team leader who designed and chose the suitable solutions for this project with high-performance and maintainable software.

Build using React, MUI, Bootstrap, and Firebase.